<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
  ~ Copyright (C) 2019 The Android Open Source Project
  ~
  ~ Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  ~ you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  ~ You may obtain a copy of the License at
  ~
  ~      http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
  ~
  ~ Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  ~ distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  ~ WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  ~ See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  ~ limitations under the License.
  -->
<tutorialBundle
    name="What's New"
    resourceRoot="/"
    stepByStep="false"
    hideStepIndex="true"
    version="4.1.08">
  <feature name="What's New in 4.1">
    <tutorial key="whats-new"
              label=" What's New in 4.1"
              icon="preview/whats_new_icon.png"
              remoteLink="https://d.android.com/r/studio-ui/whats-new-assistant/canary-release-notes.html#4.1"
              remoteLinkLabel="Read in a browser">
      <description>
        <![CDATA[
This panel describes some of the new features and behavior changes included in this update. <br><br> To open this panel again later, select <b>Help &gt; What's New in Android Studio</b> from the main menu.
]]>
      </description>
      <step label="New Database Inspector">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
<img src="https://d.android.com/studio/releases/assistant/4.1.0/database-inspector-wna.gif" width="428"> <br><br> Inspect, query, and modify your databases in your running app using the new <b>Database Inspector</b>. To get started, deploy your app to a device running API level 26 or higher, and select <b>View > Tool Windows > Database Inspector</b> from the menu bar. <a href="https://d.android.com/studio/preview/features?utm_source=android-studio-4-1&utm_medium=studio-assistant-preview#database-inspector">Learn more</a>
]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
        <stepElement>
          <action
              key="app.inspection.show"
              label="Open Database Inspector">
          </action>
        </stepElement>
      </step>
      <step label="Improved instrumentation testing">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
<br> <img src="https://d.android.com/studio/releases/assistant/4.1.0/instrumentation-test-panel-wna.png" width="428"> <br><br> Starting in Android Studio 4.1 Canary 8, instrumentation tests can now be run across multiple devices in parallel and investigated using a specialized instrumentation test results panel. Using this panel, you can determine if tests are failing due to API level or hardware properties. <br><br>Testing your app across a wide variety of API levels and form factors is one of the best ways to ensure that all users have a great experience when using your app. <br><br> <a href="https://d.android.com/studio/preview/features?utm_source=android-studio-4-1&utm_medium=studio-assistant-preview#instrumentation-testing">Learn more</a> <br>
]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
      </step>
      <step label="Dagger navigation support">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
<img src="https://d.android.com/studio/releases/assistant/4.1.0/dagger-navigation-support-wna.gif" alt="IDE gutter actions for navigating to Dagger consumers and providers" /> <br><br> Android Studio makes it easier to navigate between your Dagger-related code by providing new gutter actions and extending support in the <b>Find Usages</b> window. <br><br> <ul> <li><b>New gutter actions:</b> For projects that use Dagger, the IDE provides gutter actions that help you navigate between your Dagger-annotated code. For example, clicking on the <img src="https://d.android.com/studio/images/buttons/navigate-to-dagger-provider.png"/> gutter action next to a method that consumes a given type navigates you to the provider of that type. Conversely, clicking on the <img src="https://d.android.com/studio/images/buttons/navigate-to-dagger-consumer.png"/> gutter action navigates you to where a type is used as a dependency. </li> <li><b>Find Usages node:</b> When you invoke <b>Find Usages</b> on a provider of a given type, the <b>Find</b> window now includes a <b>Dependency consumer(s)</b> node that lists consumers of that type. Conversely, invoking this action on a consumer of a Dagger-injected dependency, the <b>Find</b> window shows you the provider of that dependency. </li> </ul> <a href="https://d.android.com/studio/preview/features?utm_source=android-studio-4-1&utm_medium=studio-assistant-preview#dagger-navigation">Learn more</a> <br><br>
]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
      </step>
      <step label="Run the Android Emulator directly in Studio">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
<img src="https://d.android.com/studio/releases/assistant/4.1.0/emulator-window-wna.gif" alt="The emulator launching in a tool window in Android Studio."/> <br><br> You can now run the Android Emulator directly in Android Studio. Use this feature to conserve screen real estate, to navigate quickly between the emulator and the editor window using hotkeys, and to organize your IDE and emulator workflow in a single application window. <br><br> To run the emulator in Android Studio, make sure you're using Android Studio 4.1 with version 30.0.10 or higher of the Android Emulator, then follow these steps: <br><br> <ol> <li>Click <strong>File > Settings > Tools > Emulator</strong> (or <strong>Android Studio > Preferences > Tools > Emulator</strong> on macOS), then select <strong>Launch in a tool window</strong> and click <strong>OK</strong>.</li> <li>If the Emulator window doesn't automatically appear, open it by clicking <strong>View > Tool Windows > Emulator</strong>.</li> <li>Start your virtual device using the <strong>AVD Manager</strong> or by targeting it when running your app.</li> </ol> <a href="https://d.android.com/studio/preview/features?utm_source=android-studio-4-1&utm_medium=studio-assistant-preview#run-emulator-studio">Learn more</a> <br><br>
]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
      </step>
      <step label="Native Memory Profiler">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
The Android Studio Memory Profiler now includes a Native Memory Profiler that tracks allocations and deallocations of objects in native code for a specific time period, providing information about the objects' size and number to help you debug issues related to memory consumption. The Native Memory Profiler has a sample size of 32 bytes and is available for apps deployed to physical devices running Android 10 or later. <br><br> <a href="https://developer.android.com/r/studio-ui/native-memory-profiler">Learn more</a> <br><br>
]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
      </step>
      <step label="Use TensorFlow Lite models">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
ML Model Binding makes it easy for you to directly import <b>.tflite</b> model files and use them in your projects. Android Studio generates easy-to-use classes so you can run your model with less code and better type safety. The current implementation of ML Model Binding supports image classification models, provided they are enhanced with metadata. Over time, support will be expanded to other problem domains, like style transfer, object detection, image segmentation, and text classification. <br><br> <a href="https://developer.android.com/r/studio-ui/tensor-flow-lite-model-binding">Learn more</a> <br><br>
]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
      </step>
      <step label="Support for Jetpack Compose">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
<a href="http://d.android.com/jetpack?utm_source=android-studio-4-0&utm_medium=studio-assistant-preview">Jetpack Compose</a> is a modern toolkit for building native Android UI. The toolkit also brings all of Kotlin's benefits, such as helping you to write concise and idiomatic code that's fully interoperable with Java. <br><br> When using Android Studio to develop your app with Jetpack Compose, you benefit from smart editor features, such as a New Project template, code completion enhancements, and a live preview of your Compose UI. <br><br> To learn more, go to the <a href="https://d.android.com/jetpack/compose?utm_source=android-studio-4-1&utm_medium=studio-assistant-preview">Jetpack Compose overview</a>. <br><br>
]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
      </step>
      <step label="Assertions in debug builds">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
When you build the deploy the debug version of your app using Android Gradle plugin 4.1.0 and higher, the built-in compiler (D8) rewrites your app's code to enable assertions at compile time, so you always have assertion checks active. <br><br> <b>Note:</b> This feature currently supports only apps written in Java. <br><br>
]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
      </step>
      <step label="Apply Changes">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
To help you be more productive as you iterate on your app, we’ve made the following enhancements to Apply Changes for devices running Android 11 Developer Preview 3 or higher: <br><br> <ul> <li>Faster deploy speeds.</li> <li>Support for adding methods, static final primitive fields, and resources.</li> </ul> <a href="https://developer.android.com/r/studio-wna/4.1.0/apply-changes">Learn more</a> <br><br>
]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
      </step>
      <footerStep label="">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[ <br><em>Last updated 4/27/2020</em><br><br> ]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
      </footerStep>
    </tutorial>
  </feature>
</tutorialBundle>