<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
  ~ Copyright (C) 2019 The Android Open Source Project
  ~
  ~ Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  ~ you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  ~ You may obtain a copy of the License at
  ~
  ~      http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
  ~
  ~ Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  ~ distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  ~ WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  ~ See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  ~ limitations under the License.
  -->
<tutorialBundle
    name="What's New"
    resourceRoot="/"
    stepByStep="false"
    hideStepIndex="true"
    version="2022.3.1.1">
  <feature
      name="What's New in Giraffe">
    <tutorial
        key="whats-new"
        label=" What's New in Giraffe"
        icon="preview/whats_new_icon.png"
        remoteLink="https://d.android.com/r/studio-ui/whats-new-assistant/preview-release-notes/2022-3-1"
        remoteLinkLabel="Read in a browser">
      <description>
        <![CDATA[
          This panel describes some of the new features and behavior changes
          included in this update.
          <br><br>
          To open this panel again later, select <b>Help &gt; What's New in Android Studio</b>
          from the main menu.
          ]]>
      </description>
      <step label="New Logcat">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
            <img src="https://d.android.com/studio/releases/assistant/2021.3.1/logcat-logs.png"/>
             <br /><br />
              <p>
                Logcat has been updated to make it easier to parse, query, and keep track of logs.
                This represents the most significant update to the tool since its introduction, and
                we welcome you to <a href="http://issuetracker.google.com/createIssue?title=%5BLogcatV2%5D+Title&cc=adarshf%40google.com%2Crpaquay%40google.com&format=PLAIN&component=192708&type=BUG&priority=P1&severity=S2&assignee=aalbert%40google.com&inProd=true">provide
                feedback</a>.
            </p>
            <br />
            <p>
              <b>New formatter:</b> Logcat now formats logs to make it easier to scan useful
              information, such as tags and messages, and identify different types of logs, such as
              warnings and errors.
            </p>
            <br />
            <p>
              <b>Create multiple Logcat windows:</b> You can now create multiple tabs within Logcat,
              so that you can easily switch between different devices or queries. Right-clicking a
              tab allows you to rename it, and you can click and drag to rearrange the tabs.
              Additionally, to help you more easily compare between two sets of logs, you can now
              split the view within a tab by right-clicking in the log view and selecting either
              <b>Split Right</b> or <b>Split Down</b>.
            </p>
            <br />
            <p>
              <b>Switch between view presets:</b> Logcat now allows you to quickly switch between
                different view modes (<b>Standard</b>, <b>Compact</b>, and <b>Custom</b>) by clicking
                <img src="https://d.android.com/studio/releases/assistant/2021.3.1/logcat-view-modes-button.png">.
                Each view mode provides a different default setting for showing you more or less
                information, such as timestamps, tags, and process IDs (PID). You can also customize each of
                these default view modes, as well as a custom view mode, by selecting <b>Modify View</b>.
            </p>
              <br><img src="https://d.android.com/studio/releases/assistant/2021.3.1/logcat-view-selection.png"></p>
              <br><br>
            <p>
              <b>New key-value search:</b> We've now simplified the search experience by introducing
              key-value searches right from the main query field, complete with suggestions, history,
              and the ability to favourite queries.
            </p>
              <br><img src="https://d.android.com/studio/releases/assistant/2021.3.1/logcat-query-auto-complete.png"></p>
              <br><br>
            <p>
              Here are some examples of how to use the new query system, but you can also simply
              start typing in the query field to see suggestions:
            </p>
            <br />
            <ul>
              <li><b>PIDs for the local app project:</b> <code>package:mine</code>
              </li>
              <li><b>Specific values:</b> <code>package:my-package-ID</code>, <code>tag:my-tag</code>,
              <code>level:ERROR</code>, and more.
              </li>
              <li><b>Exclude a specific value</b> by preceding the key with <code>-</code>:
              <code>-tag:exclude-this-tag</code>.
              </li>
              <li><b>Use regular expressions</b> with a given key by placing a <code>~</code> after the key:
              <code>tag~:regex-tag</code> or <code>-tag~:exclude-this-regex-tag</code>.
              </li>
            </ul>
            <br />
            <p>You can also see a history of queries by clicking
            <img src="https://d.android.com/studio/releases/assistant/2021.3.1/logcat-query-history.png">
            in the query field and selecting them from the drop down. To favorite a query so that it
            stays at the top of the list across all your studio projects, click the
            <img src="https://d.android.com/studio/releases/assistant/2021.3.1/logcat-favourite.png">
            at the end of the query field.
            </p>
              <br><img src="https://d.android.com/studio/releases/assistant/2021.3.1/logcat-history.png"></p>
              <br><br>
            <p><b>Track logs across app crashes/restarts:</b> The new Logcat now makes it easier to
            track logs from your app across app crashes and restarts, so that you don't miss important
            logs across these events. When a Logcat notices that your app process has stopped and
            restarted you'll see a message in the output similar to below:
            </p>
              <br><img src="https://d.android.com/studio/releases/assistant/2021.3.1/logcat-app-restart.png"></p>
              <br><br>
              <a href="https://d.android.com/studio/preview/features#logcat">Learn more</a>
              <br><br>
            ]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
      </step>
      <step label="Live Edit for composables">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
            <p>
            Make code changes to composables in Android Studio and see those changes reflected
            immediately in the Compose Preview and your emulator or physical device. You don't have
            to wait for builds or deployments to be completed, so you can make faster progress in
            the creation of your app's experience.
            </p>
            <br>
            <a href="https://d.android.com/r/studio-ui/compose/live-edit">Learn more</a>
            <br>
            <br>
            ]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
      </step>
      <step label="SDK insights">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
            <p>
            Get Lint warnings for SDKs or libraries that have been marked as outdated by their
            authors in the Google Play SDK Index. Update outdated dependency versions during
            development to avoid issues when your app is submitted to the Play Console.
            </p>
            <br>
            <a href="https://d.android.com/r/studio-ui/build/sdk-insights">Learn more</a>
            <br>
            <br>
            ]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
      </step>
      <step label="App Quality Insights from Firebase Crashlytics">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
            <p>
            Discover, investigate, and resolve issues reported by Crashlytics in Android Studio and
            within the context of your local source code. This integration helps you quickly
            navigate from crashes to code (and from code to crash), and surfaces important
            contextual data about each crash to help you reproduce issues locally. If your app
            project already includes the Crashlytics SDK, get started by selecting
            <b>View &gt; Tool windows &gt; App Quality Insights<b> from the main menu.
            </p>
            <br>
            <a href="https://d.android.com/r/studio-ui/debug/aqi">Learn more</a>
            <br>
            <br>
            ]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
      </step>
      <step label="Resizable Emulator">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
            <p>
            Rapidly toggle between representative reference devices to quickly test various
            application layout states with a single running emulator instance. You can create these
            emulators by selecting the "Resizable" type in the Device Manager's "Create device"
            flow.
            </p>
            <br>
            <a href="https://d.android.com/r/studio-ui/run/resizable-emulator">Learn more</a>
            <br>
            <br>
            ]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
      </step>
      <step label="Visual Linting">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
            <p>
            Discover and fix your layout issues across different devices by opening the Layout
            Validation panel. We automatically run your layout to check for Visual Lint issues
            across different screen sizes.
            </p>
            <br>
            <a href="https://d.android.com/r/studio-ui/layout/visual-linting">Learn more</a>
            <br>
            <br>
            ]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
      </step>
      <step label="Emulated Bluetooth">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
            <p>
            You can now discover and connect two phone emulators using virtual Bluetooth. With
            virtual Bluetooth, you can test that your app can recognize and gain access to the
            Bluetooth adapter in a scalable way.
            </p>
            <br>
            <a href="https://d.android.com/r/studio-ui/run/emulated-bluetooth">Learn more</a>
            <br>
            <br>
            ]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
      </step>
      <step label="Device Mirroring">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
            <p>
               Minimize the number of interruptions when developing by streaming your device display
               directly to Android Studio. Device Mirroring gives you the ability to interact with a
               physical device using the <b>Running Devices</b> window in Studio. To enable this feature,
               go to <b>Preferences > Experimental</b> and check the box next to <b>Device Mirroring</b>.
               Once enabled, connect your device and either deploy your app or open the
               <b>Running Devices</b> window to begin streaming the device's display and interacting
               with it from the IDE.
            </p><br><br>
            ]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
      </step>
      <step label="New Wear OS run configurations">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
              <p>
                New run configurations have been added to quickly run and debug surfaces specific
                to <a href="https://d.android.com/training/wearables">Wear OS</a> like watch faces, Tiles, and complications.
                You can create these new configurations from the <b>Run/Debug Configurations</b> dialog
                when running your application.
              </p>
              <img src="https://d.android.com/studio/preview/features/images/dolphin/wearos_launch_configurations.png"/>

              <p>
                Alternatively, you can also run these surfaces from the gutter icon that is
                located next to the declaration of the surface, as shown in the following image.
             </p>
             <img src="https://d.android.com/studio/preview/features/images/dolphin/wearos_os_gutter_run.png"/>
           ]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
      </step>
      <footerStep label="">
        <stepElement>
          <section>
            <![CDATA[
              <br><em>Last updated 12/13/2022</em><br><br>
            ]]>
          </section>
        </stepElement>
      </footerStep>
    </tutorial>
  </feature>
</tutorialBundle>